Harish V Hariharan

Director- Multinational OEMs at Microsoft

Summary

Senior Business Leader with diverse experience in Sales, Marketing and Business Development with Enterprise, Mid-Market & Small Business, in Indian Sub-continent & USA in the domains of Software Products & Services, Consumer & Business Computing Devices, Enterprise Hardware & Software Solutions and Systems Integration. Over 20 years of experience in Strategic Account Management, Business Development, building Channel Eco-system & P&L management across leading Global Technology companies such as Wipro, IBM, Lenovo & Microsoft. Established track record of driving business growth and building trusted relationships with Customers and Partners.

Experience

Director- Multinational OEMs at Microsoft

2013 - Present (4 years)

Sales, Market Share and Marketing Strategy with two of Microsoft's largest Global Hardware OEM Customers. I bring my experience of the Computing Devices ecosystem in building strategic growth plans with my OEMs to deliver mutual revenue and growth objectives. Strong Results in Revenue Growth, Share of Microsoft Stack, Innovations with Digital Transformation and Cloud Offerings and Customer Satisfaction.

Director- Named OEMs at Microsoft Corporation India Pvt.Ltd.

2008 - 2013 (5 years)

Sales, Market Share and Strategy with Indian Named OEM Accounts including IT giants like HCL, Wipro, Zenith Computers, that represented the biggest revenue and margin contributors to Microsoft in India. I managed Named OEMs businesses in South and West initially and subsequently assumed national responsibility for Named OEM business. Recruited new OEMs, grew business with existing ones & delivered Business Results through a turbulent phase for Local Hardware Industry.

General Manager - SMB Transaction at Lenovo India Pvt Ltd

2007 - 2008 (1 year)

Segment & sales leadership for Small & Medium Business for Lenovo India with P&L responsibility. led a Pan-India team of SMB Managers. Collaborated with v-teams on 4P strategy, oversaw channel relationships and drove execution rigor for business results.

SMS&P Leader at Microsoft

2004 - 2007 (3 years)

Helped set up the subsidiary as employee # 2. Initially managed all customer segments, and later assumed role as Small, Mid-Sized Business & Partner (SMS&P) Leader, building the widest Partner Ecosystem with a team of high performance sales people. Collaborated with Country Manager on building the 3 year Subsidiary blue-print.

Business Development Manager- Emerging Markets at Microsoft

2001 - 2004 (3 years)

Executed entry and growth strategy for Microsoft in Sri Lanka and Bangladesh, leading up to the setting up of independent Microsoft subsidiaries per plan time-line. Established new Market Development Partner model, grew customer & partner ecosystem, worked with Government Entities for frameworks for copyright protection and Government-Microsoft MOU. A notable outcome of our efforts was the enactment of the Intellectual Property (IPR) Law of Sri Lanka. Full accountability for Sales Targets & Market Share Growth driving over 2.5X revenue growth.

Business Development Manager at Silverline Technologies

2001 - 2001 (less than a year)

Business Development in strategic e-business, B2B & Legacy IT Transformation services. Generated new service and solutions opportunities with Fortune 500 prospects

Client Relationship Manager- Business Partners at IBM India Private Limited

2000 - 2001 (1 year)

Relationship & Business Goals with Business Partners in TN/Kerala for IBM Personal Systems, Enterprise Systems & Software.

Large Accounts Manager at IBM India Private Limited

1999 - 2000 (1 year)

Winning and Growing IBMs share of wallet in key corporate accounts in TN/Kerala

Business Partner Relationship Manager at IBM India Private Limited

1996 - 1999 (3 years)

Responsible for revenue growth for IBM Personal Systems Group Products through identified resellers in South India. Relationship & Pan-India Revenue growth for a national partner

Territory Manager at Wipro Infotech Ltd

1993 - 1996 (3 years)

Sales & Business Development in Kolkata & East India for Sun Microsystems Products. Account Management of Marquee Manufacturing Segment Accounts in Tamil Nadu & New Customer acquisition for Wipro's SI offerings, including Sun, Symix ERP and Integrated Networking solutions. Key Outcomes: First Sun Workstation order & the single largest Integrated Sun-Network deal in the East. First Symix ERP Win in South India. Several competition Account acquisitions.

Education

Faculty of Management Studies - University of Delhi

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Marketing & Finance, 1991 - 1993

Indian Institute of Technology (Banaras Hindu University), Varanasi

B Tech, Mechanical Engineering, 1987 - 1991

Activities and Societies: Tennis, Spicmacay

DAV Jawahar Vidya Mandir, Ranchi

High School

Certifications

Microsoft-INSEAD Online Business Strategy and Financial Acumen

INSEAD Executive Education October 2015

Skills & Expertise

Product Management

Solution Selling

Pre-sales

Business Development

Team Management

Leadership

Sales & Marketing

Account Management

Vendor Management

Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Strategy

Partner Management

Business Strategy

Go-to-market Strategy

Channel Partners

Digital Marketing

Digital Transformation

Alliance Sales

Management

Sales Management

Market Research

Microsoft Office

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency)

Hindi (Full professional proficiency)

Tamil (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Honors and Awards

2015:Outstanding Field Execution; Partner Ecosystem Impact; Business Transformation

2013: Collaboration: SMS&P Bi-annual Innovation Award for H1

2011: Microsoft Circle of Excellence: Gold Club Award

Globally recognized Area Award in Microsoft for contribution to success & growth of Microsoft

2010: Microsoft Gold Star award – Special award for out-standing revenue contribution

"Outstanding performance and excellence in Marketing"

Wipro Infotech Ltd

1995

"Significant breakthrough into competition accounts"

Wipro Infotech Ltd

1996

"Outstanding Performance in the achievement of functional objectives"

IBM India Limited

1998

"Contribution above and beyond the call of duty"

IBM

1999

Harish V Hariharan

Director- Multinational OEMs at Microsoft



4 people have recommended Harish V

"Working with Harish for over 2 years on Acer account, he has been the most trusted partner in the field to me. An individual with high business integrity and tones of experience about India PC ecosystem, allows the people who is partnering with him to leverage on his expertise to achieve more locally. Looking forward to continue partnering with Harish to drive more business with Acer in the coming years for MSFT."

— Candice Yin, Regional Marketing Lead- Asia (Acer), OEM Division, Microsoft, worked with Harish V at Microsoft

"Harish is a details oriented and customer focused professional, who has proven major account management experience. He has always come across as laser focused on results and relies on deep analysis of every situation to ensure delivery of outcomes. Above all, Harish brings depth in every conversation given his understanding of the business and 'much above average' command over the English language. It's been a pleasure working with Harish."

— **Deepanshu Sharma**, *Director - Business Operations*, *Microsoft Corporation*, worked directly with Harish V at Microsoft

"I worked with Harish when he was managing the Named Account as the OEM Director in Microsoft. He was by far one of the hardest working, conscientious, and focussed account leads in OEM. The OEM's he managed were lucky to have someone like him represent them within Microsoft, and he thought of everything he could do to help them get a leg-up in the PC business they were in. He is a great resource for Microsoft and if he ever looks at other opportunities, think of him as an immediate choice."

— **Haja Sheriff**, *Multinational Account Director*, *OEM India, Microsoft Corporation India Pvt Ltd*, worked directly with Harish V at Microsoft Corporation India Pvt.Ltd.

"Harish is strategic in his thinking and has a real strong understanding of the Channel. This gives him a unique ability to leverage the channel ecosystem in order to drive business results. His ability to build industry relationships and structure path breaking collaborations with partners as with large entities can be a game changer for any organisation he represents. He is an asset to any team."

— **Kishore Modak**, Segment Manager/Business Unit Manager / Marketing Manager (Personal Computing Division, IBM India Ltd, worked with Harish V at Wipro Infotech Ltd

Contact Harish V on LinkedIn